Michael Arvelo

Software Engineer m.arvelo@live.com

(786) 314-8003 3100 W Rolling Hills Cir, Apt 308 Davie, FL 33328

Summary

Software engineer with 5+ years experience developing robust code. Currently working on various internal web applications at Citrix. Worked on MVC Suite of Web Applications for Public Housing Authorities (C#, .NET MVC, Razor, Javascript/JQuery, MetroUI, AmazonS3, Azure). Worked with a team that migrated entire Delphi code base to .NET ahead of time utilizing Unity to implement dependency injection and onion architecture for a loosely coupled solution. Utilizing SOLID principles, I can build testable, maintainable, and extensible software.

Experience

Software Engineer @ Citrix

May 2018 - present

- Utilized JIRA for tracking agile and development projects.
- Maintained suite of internal web applications for tracking finances, creating new projects, and adding new Citrix employees which utilized PHP, C#, Javascript/JQuery, VB, and SQL.
- Utilized GIT/Jenkins for source control and deployment.

Software Developer @ Emphasys Software

Jan 2015- May 2018

- Worked on web application (Housing Services) for applying to waiting lists, checking various statuses, and submitting recent data which utilized .NET MVC, Razor, Azure, Metro UI, OWIN, SQL, and Javascript/JQuery.
- Worked on mobile application (using Xamarin/MVVM) used by inspectors for managing inspection details.
- Utilized SCRUM/Kanban within TFS to create and work on user stories and to demonstrate progress to stakeholders to receive feedback.
- Worked on massive effort for converting legacy Delphi application to .NET using C#, EF, XAML, MVVM, Onion Architecture, Unity IOC, and WCF.
- Created and refactored various stored procedures for different modules, advanced accounting calculations, and various reusable SQL scripts for solving service cases.
- Designed new databases using best practices with normalization.

Programming Tutor @ Miami Dade College

August 2012 - December 2014

- Developed a passion for software engineering while tutoring C++, Visual Basic, Java, and most intro Computer Science courses.
- Teachers' assistant for all Computer Science related courses.

Skills

Languages

C# and .NET, Java, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Delphi, PHP, VB, XAML

Technologies/Frameworks

Azure DevOps, AmazonS3, JQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, MetroUI, Jenkins, GIT, TFS, MVVM, WPF, MVC, Razor, OAUTH/OWIN, Katana, Unity IOC, WCF, Entity Framework, LINQ, NUnit, Selenium UI, VSCode, Xamarin

Education

Florida International University

2013